Mother, how can we please You best?
There is a good question Shri Mataji:
How can we please You best?
Shri Mataji: I have no desires.
I don’t know [Laughter; applause].
You see, inside Me is complete peace
and complete satisfaction.
There is nothing that is needed inside.
But the ripples of that joy flow outward all the time.
And when it reaches your shores, you see, it comes back.
And it weaves a beautiful pattern,
The reciprocity, how much you reciprocate is the way the pattern is beautiful.
pattern is beautiful. It’s delicate,
it’s powerful. It’s so soothing
and it weaves the complete beauty of bhakti.
So much so that this ocean of joy itself gets turbulent,
and I really swing with it. And it is not easy to describe that beautiful feeling of tremendous joy.
The first thing you have to know that  I love you very much,
with all my heart, with all my soul.
In the same way, try to love Me with all sincerity and trust.
May God bless you all!
Now I’ll speak for one minute about this meditation.
Yesterday I told you about putting your attention to different areas,
the “pradesha” [region] or the chakras.
And the chakra, as you know, has got “mandalas” [orb], it’s the areas.
So, when you pay attention to the chakras, where do you pay attention to,
is the point.
Actually, you pay attention to the deity.
Now this deity- supposing you are taking the name of Shri Rama,
you are trying to establish Shri Rama within your heart, Right Heart Chakra.
Now at that time, what do you do?
You say the mantra.
But there’s another way which is easier. Because you are saying a mantra
in a way that is not so much intelligible there,
to Shri Rama. But first of all, if you study the qualities of Shri Rama,
what were his qualities?
And if you manifest those qualities through your character,
then it’s very easy to please Shri Rama.
What is the quality of Shri Ganesha?
He’s entirely surrendered to Mother,
even Father doesn’t bother Him.
What is the quality of Christ?
He forgives those who have crucified Him.
He can go through all kinds of tapasya.
What is the quality of Shri Krishna
for whom everything is a leela?
Like that, when you take the name of Shri Krishna,
do you see everything as a witness?
If effortlessly that happens to you, you should know that you have established Shri Krishna.
It’s the most difficult thing, is to establish Me because I am Mahamaya
to establish Me." because I am Mahamaya,
And the facets are so many:
sixteen thousand into, raised to power one thousand.
So, it’s difficult. But whatever things you can grasp and think, “
and think this is Mother's quality,
try to imbibe that within yourself.
That doesn't mean you start
shouting at Bhoots first.
So, first, what is the first quality of Mother?
That She came on this earth and She has worked for people
who are nowhere near Her.
She stooped down to elevate others.
And then gradually you can understand that
that this quality will take you to higher qualities than you think.
So, among the seven colours to begin with, I am the green colour.
because I am in the centre.
Because I’m in the centre. Green colour is the colour that you get it from the Mother Earth.
So first you must establish the quality of the Mother Earth
that she sucks up all the problems, gives you the best that she has.
Start with the Mother Earth, so you start with the Kundalini.
That’s how one should start imbibing the pure Kundalini form of Mother, is purity,
In imbibing the pure Kundalini form of Mother, is purity,
is cleansing purity.
But are you pure?
Are you pure in your heart?
Just think of that. And then, with purity you start.
That is how you have to establish different chakras,
of purifying all the chakras  and ultimately when you have purified all of them,
you have established Me.
Thus, we understand we have to grow within and without
by spreading our light horizontally now.
Only when you become like the deities your light will spread horizontally,
otherwise not.
That is what we say that somebody has got the “siddha” [power]
of a particular deity, is the siddha of Ganesha, is the siddha of Shri Krishna.
So first, when you develop their manifesting outside powers,  you see,
of kindness, compassion, of witness and all those,
then you can develop their other qualities, which are on the destructive side.
Which are on the destructive side.
First the constructive side you must develop, then the destructive automatically will work,
You don't have to worry.
Like one side of Shri Krishna,
He was playing with with ordinary herds men
and the- another side, he was killing rakshasas.
So first, you have to become like Him and then
automatically you will get the other powers.
You don’t give swords to stupid people, do you?
So one would understand
that one has to develop these qualities
of construction of all the incarnations and then you become
empowered by the destructive qualities of those incarnations.
If you understand the sequence, then the fanaticism will never grow
because fanaticism comes  when you start thinking that you are the incarnation or
whatever incarnation has done, you can do.
thinking that you are the incarnation, or
Like Christians felt they could become Kalki without His Advent even.
And they took a piece, a rifle or you can say, a gun in one hand
and the Bible in another hand.
And the Muslims, they never believed that Mohammad was a prophet [an incarnation].
So they think because he was not a prophet- he was a prophet but he was not an incarnation.
So, we could also do the same what he was doing.”
In the same way, Hindus also, when they become fanatic,
they start thinking they have become great incarnations.
So, discretion must be used again
that you develop all the constructive side of an incarnation.
So, after the seminar you have to remember my word about it
that you have to concentrate on a deity to imbibe the qualities of that deity.
Otherwise you have no communication with the deity, and no use saying the mantras.
Like we would say that, “My this chakra is catching or that chakra is catching.” Why?
"That chakra is catching." Why?
Because there is that lacking of that chakra that you have not yet imbibed within yourself.
So you must try to identify yourself with the qualities,
the constructive qualities of every deity
and that’s how you should believe that you are now correcting your chakras with the mantras.
Otherwise I’ll find all the Sahaja yogis carrying all the thousand weapons of the Devi in their hands, suddenly
thinking they have all become Devis.
Now I hope when you go back home, you won’t forget my words
and try to concentrate on your pradesha, on your areas of different chakras
which are not all right and which are troubling you.
And try to imbibe those qualities. And nourish, nourish also the ones that are all right
by understanding the qualities of the deities.
Then only you will be amazed that your powers will flow without even thinking about it. It’s not difficult for you,
it is not at all difficult.
But know that instead of paying attention to other’s chakras better look after your own chakras.
If your chakras are all right, you won’t even catch from others.
Another dangerous thing people do is to correct the chakras of others.
Individually it should never be done, collectively you may do.
But it’s better not to enter into that exercise till you have reached certain state of confidence.
This is for your further movement into the second era of Sahaja Yoga.
And I hope I will live to see the second era fully.
Gregoire: Until the third, fourth one?
Shri Mataji: But first second one. You desire for the second. You cannot jump, you know.
Now here you should today say to yourself that in your heart promise that,
“Mother I will now correct myself completely for my own benefit
and I will project my mind to think discreetly how I can help to propagate Sahaja Yoga to others.”
With discretion, we should not go and talk to a bull about Sahaja Yoga.